สั่งอะไรดีคะ
What would you like to order?
Today you'll learn 8 phrases to order food in Thai like a local.
When I first moved to Bangkok, there was this noodle stall near my apartment. Every morning, the same aunty would shout at me — สั่งอะไรดีคะ — and I had no idea what to say. I just pointed at the picture.
สั่งอะไรดีคะ
By the end of this video, you won't need to point. You'll order in Thai, ask for recommendations, tell them how spicy you want it, and get the bill — all in Thai.
สั่ง
คุณอยากสั่งอะไร
เผ็ด
ไม่เผ็ด
ไม่เอาเผ็ดนะคะ
อร่อย
อร่อยมาก
ขอ
ขอผัดไทยหนึ่งจานค่ะ
เก็บเงิน
เก็บเงินด้วยค่ะ
แนะนำ
แนะนำอะไรดีคะ
อิ่ม
อิ่มแล้วค่ะ
แนะนำอะไรดีคะ
ขอผัดไทยหนึ่งจานค่ะ
ไม่เอาเผ็ดนะคะ
อร่อยมาก
อิ่มแล้วค่ะ
เก็บเงินด้วยค่ะ
แนะนำอะไรดีคะ
náe-nam a-rai dii khá
What do you recommend?
ขอผัดไทยหนึ่งจานค่ะ
khǎaw phàt-thai nùeng jaan khâ
I'd like one Pad Thai, please.
ไม่เอาเผ็ดนะคะ
mâi ao phèt ná khá
No spicy, please.
อร่อยมาก
a-ròoy mâak
Very delicious!
เก็บเงินด้วยค่ะ
gèp ngern dûuay khâ
Can I have the bill, please?
How would you say: 'I'd like one Pad Thai, please'?
Try saying it now...
ขอผัดไทยหนึ่งจานค่ะ
How would you say: 'No spicy, please'?
Try saying it now...
ไม่เอาเผ็ดนะคะ
How would you say: 'Can I have the bill, please'?
Try saying it now...
เก็บเงินด้วยค่ะ
แนะ นำ อะไร ดี คะ
ขอ ผัด ไทย หนึ่ง จาน ค่ะ
ไม่ เอา เผ็ด นะ คะ
อร่อย มาก
อิ่ม แล้ว ค่ะ
เก็บ เงิน ด้วย ค่ะ
Quick recap — here are your 8 phrases for ordering food in Thai.
Next time — asking for directions. You'll learn how to say 'where is...?' and understand the answer.
...อยู่ที่ไหนคะ